zynaptiq.com 2019-07-27

# zynaptiq: privacy

This privacy policy describes how and why Zynaptiq GmbH (“Zynaptiq”, “we” or “us”) processes your personal data when you access or use any part of the Website [ www.zynaptiq.com](http://zynaptiq.com/index.php) (the “Website“), shop online, install, activate or use our software, communicate or interact with us in any other way. This privacy policy is meant to help you understand what data we may collect, under whch circumstances we collect it, why we collect it and what we do with it. You will also find information about how you can affect the processing of your personal data and what rights you have. 

## What is personal data?

Personal data means any information relating to you that, directly or indirectly, may be used to identify you, for example your name and your e-mail address. Information such as your IP-number and your user behavior when using the Website may also be personal data. 

## Who is responsible for processing your personal data?

When your personal data is being processed by us for our purposes, in the way set out in this Privacy Policy, Zynaptiq GmbH, registered with number HRB 208004 at Amtsgericht Hannover, is the data controller regarding such processing. 

If you have any questions about our processing of your personal data or your rights connected hereto, you can always contact us. 

## Which sources for personal data about you do we have, and which data do we receive from them?

Most of the personal data that we process about you is information that you have chosen to provide to us.  
 We gather such information about you when:

  * You order a trial version of our software. We deliver download information per email, for which you must provide a valid address for an email account to which you have access. You must also select the operating system for which you wish to use the software. You may also optionally provide additional information such as your name, your preferred host application, and your main field of work. You may subscribe to our email newsletter when ordering a trial version.
 
  * You register your software. After purchasing a zynaptiq software product, you must register your software in order to receive download URLs as well as license activation codes; you can not use our software without registration. When you register your software, you must provide your name, a valid address for an email account to which you have access, as well as the registration code provided by your dealer. In addition, we log the IP address from which the registration was performed, along with a timestamp, and information about the browser and OS used to perform the registration. 
 
  * You navigate this website; our content management system will create access log files that may contain information about your IP address, operating system, browser, the date and time of the access request, and the pages you visited. We rarely use this information; when we do, it typically relates mainly to evaluating website usability, functionality and security.
 
  * You contact us in any way (for example contacting our customer service or at social media channels). We may gather whatever information you provide to us voluntarily and thus assumedly with consent. 

We receive such data about you from third parties when:

  * You navigate this website; our hosting services provider will create access log files that may contain information about your IP address, operating system, browser, the date and time of the access request, and the pages you visited.
 
  * You purchase from our reseller partner Digital River, Inc., owners of the brand "eSellerate". eSellerate is a third-party reseller based outside of the EU/EEA, and subject to their own Privacy Policy which you should evaluate before making a purchase at [cs.mycommerce.com/privacy-policy/esellerate](http://cs.mycommerce.com/privacy-policy/esellerate) . We administrate their Zynaptiq shop for them, and manage most related support issues. In order for us to be able to perform such administration, we receive transactional data relating to your purchase that consists of a purchaser's name, email address, billing address, payment method, date, time and IP address of purchase, order number, and similar data needed to provide warranty, facilitate returns, and provide information about order status.
 
  * You activate your license for our software. To use our software – all license types, including full, NFR and trials – you must have an account with PACE Anti-Piracy, Inc., a third-party company based outside of the EU/EEA, also known as "iLok". This account is used to identify you as licensed user of and provide access to our software, and stores your software licenses for you (and us). You activate our software by adding a license file to your iLok account – our software will then verify its licensing status by querying your iLok account (when activating to HD or via cloud), or an attached iLok2 or iLok 3 USB key, for a valid license. In order for us to be able to adminsistrate your licenses, provide support, and generally implement our contractual obligations to you in context of your software license, PACE provides us with that part of your data which relates directly to your licenses to our software, such as Name, email address, IP Address, and a list of and status for your Zynaptiq licenses, as well as information about the name and OS of any computers you use with our licenses. Such account can be created at the third-party website www.ilok.com , which is owned and maintained by PACE Anti-Piracy, Inc. , and which is subject to their own Privacy Policy, which you should evaluate before registering an account, at https://www.ilok.com/#!privacy-policy, and https://www.ilok.com/#!terms-of-use. Also, as a convenience, our software's activation window provides the option to launch your browser and open the iLok.com website should you need to activate the software and not yet have an iLok account; please note that when cerating such an account at ilok.com, you are doing so at a third-party site and providing data to a third party, under the terms of their Privacy Policy and Terms Of Use.
 
  * When you sign up for a survey, contest or campaign offer that we arrange together with our marketing partners; we may receive the information that you have chosen to provide to our partner with in such survey, contest or campaign offer.

## What do we do with your personal data and why do we do it?

We process your personal data for different purposes. Below you can read more about why and how we process your personal data, what legal basis we have for the processing and more. 

## When you activate or have a Zynaptiq software license

If you want to use any of our products, including trial versions, you will need to register with us. You must provide your name, a valid email address, and the Registration Code provided by your dealer. After registration, you will be entitled to 2nd level and up support, and will receive an Activation Code, which you can use to unlock the software. If you do not provide us with the personal data needed for registration, we cannot provide level 2+ support, nor an Activation Code. If you do not want to provide us with the information, you cannot use our products.  
 To use this Activation Code, you will also need an account with PACE Anti-Piracy, Inc., also known as "ilok". This account facilitates our copy protection, meaning that it is the basis of verifying licensing status and providing access to our software to you. Additionally, it is used by you and/or us to move activations between locations, transfer licenses, and more. Please see the ilok.com website to find out more about what data PACE requires and/or collects in context of such ilok account. If you do not have an iLok account, you can not use our products.

Purpose: To administer your license(s), provide support, and verify licensing status.  
  
---  
  
 **Processing made:**

  * Storing your registration data and assigning an Activation Code to your email.

  * Confirmation of your contact information

  * Administration of your purchase history connected to your Zynaptiq account in order to provide you with the updates, upgrades and discounts you are eligible for

  *   Sending you information about updates, upgrades and new releases of your purchased products. 

| 

**Personal data processed:**

  * E-mail address

  * iLok User name for license management

  * Name

  * Purchase history (for example what products and updates you have purchased)

| 

**Legal basis:**

The processing is necessary in order to verify licensing status, adminster your licenses, and for us to thereby fulfil our software license contract with you. 

Processing of such data as well as sending you information about updates, upgrades and new releases of your purchased products is necessary for the purposes of our and your legitimate interest of having updated products.

## When we communicate with each other

Purpose: To provide you with support and customer service and to communicate with you in relation to such and similar matters  
  
---  
  
 **Processing made:**

  * Confirmation of your identity and contact information

  * Communication and correspondence with you by e-mail, telephone or our digital channels

  * Reply to your comments and questions

  * Internal administration of your support matter or comments or questions to our customer service

| 

 **Personal data processed:**

  * Contact information – name and e-mail address etc

  * Information about your Zynaptiq licenses

  * Information that you provide us for example information about your Zynaptiq licenses, your iLok account, your products or the questions you ask about our products and services

  * If you contact us in our digital channels (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, YouTube): your profile name and photo

| 

 **Legal basis:**

The processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interest of helping you with your support matter or reply to your comments and questions and in order to meet your request for communication with us.

## When we analyze and develop our products and service

Purpose: To perform customer and market analyses and to evaluate our products and services in order to develop and improve our products and services for our customers  
  
---  
  
 **Processing made:**

  * Adaption of products and services in order to make them more user friendly

  * Produce documentation to develop and improve our line of products and services

  * Give our customers the possibility of affecting our line of products and services

  * Analyses of the data we collect for the purpose. Based on the data we process we make analyses (on an aggregated level without being able to identify you as an individual) which form the basis of our development of our Website and our products and services.

| 

 **Personal data processed:**

  * Information you have provided us with, for example your age, and information about your musical interests and preferences

  * Purchase and user generated data (for example information about the products you have purchased, browsed and/or added to the cart, information about the pages you have visited and time spent on our Website, what links you have clicked and what content you have watched)

  * Technical data regarding the units you use and its settings (for example IP-address, geographical location, browser settings, platform)

  * Information about how you have interacted with us

| 

 **Legal basis:**

The processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interest of evaluating, developing and improving our Website and our products and services.

## When we send you newsletters, offers or other marketing material

Purpose: To send you information about our products and services and information about special offers or campaigns.   
  
---  
  
 **Processing made:**

  * Administration and sending of newsletters with information about our products and services and information about special offers or campaigns.

  * Administration and sending of personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication so that you receive offers and information about products and services that we think you are interested in, by means of a newsletter mailing.

  * Analyses of the data we collect for the purpose. Based on the data we process we make analyses and conduct profiling (on an individual level) which form the basis of our personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication with you.

| 

**Personal data processed:**

  * E-mail address

  * Information about your Zynaptiq licenses including your purchase history and trial licenses and downloads.

  * Information about your preferred operating system

  * Information about your preferred DAW and field of work (if you have provided it to us)

  * Technical data regarding the units you use and its settings (for example IP-adress, geographical location, browser settings, platform)

  * User generated data relating to the newsletters and other communication we have sent you (for example information about your receipt and handling of our communication, including information about the e-mails you have opened, what links in the e-mails you have clicked)

| 

 **Legal basis:**

Your consent or our legitimate interest. If you want information about our products and services and information about special offers or campaigns you can sign up for our newsletters to receive news and personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication. You can withdraw your consent at any time by unsubscribing from our newsletter, and we will stop sending you newsletters containing personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication.

If you have recently purchased one of our products, we can send you newsletters containing personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication based on our legitimate interest of marketing our products and services. You have the right to object to such marketing (including to object to profiling) at any time by unsubscribing from our newsletter, and we will stop sending you newsletters containing personally adapted recommendations, offers and communication.

## When we process data in order to comply with legal obligations or to prevent abuse

Purpose: To comply with legal requirements.  
  
---  
  
 **Processing made:**

  * Any necessary processing in order to comply with legal obligations that we are subject to, for example German consumer legislation, German tax legislation, the German rules on product liability or German rules on statutes of limitation

| 

**Personal data processed:**

  * Identity and contact information.

  * Accounting details if available.

  * Information about purchased products.

  * Information about timing of purchases and possible cancellations, complaints and claims for warranties

| 

 **Legal basis:**

The processing is necessary in order for us to comply with legal obligations we are subject to. If the information is not processed we are unable to comply with our legal obligations and will therefore be forced to deny your purchase.

Purpose: To prevent and investigate abuse of our services or potential violation of law  
  
---  
  
  **Processing made:**  

  * Necessary processing in order to prevent potential violation of law

  * Necessary processing in order to protect our IT environment towards attacks and intrusions

  * Necessary processing in order to prevent unpermitted use of software licenses

  * Necessary processing in order to prevent unpermitted use of copyright and other IPR protected products

| 

  **Personal data processed:**  

  * Purchase and user generated data

  * Technical data regarding the units you use and its settings (for example IP-adress, geographical location, browser settings, platform)

  * Your license management account

  * E-mail address

| 

  **Legal basis:**  

The processing is necessary for the purpose of our legitimate interest of protecting our IT environment and our products and services from attacks and intrusions and other abuse and of protecting our and our licensors copyright protected products

## Do you want to know more about our legitimate interest?

As we have described above under “What do we do with your personal data and why do we do it?” we sometimes process your personal data based on our legitimate interest. If you have any questions about this or want to know more about how we have determined our legitimate interest, you are welcome to contact us. 

## Do we transfer your personal data to third parties?

In general: NO, we don't. The rare scenarios where we do transmit your data to third parties are a) if required by law, including tax regulation; b) with your explicit or implicit consent to resellers or local distributors in order to enable them to provide support to you. Also, we may in the future decide to work with a Privacy Shield certified third party to handle sending of email and managing mailing lists; should you have subscribed to our newsletter, you will be notified with sufficient advance notice to opt out of such transfer. 

If you want more information about the third parties that we share your personal data with, you are always welcome to contact us. 

_Partners that provide our protection system we use:_  We use iLok.com software for copy protection; we do not activaly transfer any data to PACE; however, we provide the means for you to go to their website and create an account, which is needed to use our software. When you create an iLok.com account, you will be providing data to PACE. PACE Anti-Piracy, Inc. have their business outside the EU/EEA. 

_Partners who sell our software:_  We do not activalery transfer information to our sales partners, including eSellerate (Digital River). However, we provide means for you to go to their respective websites and potentially purchase goods from there; when you do so, you will be providing data to such reseller.  Digital River, Inc. have their business outside the EU/EEA. 

_Other partners:_  We team up with different partners in order to provide you with special offers, features or contests. 

_In the event of a transfer of assets or shares:_  If Zynaptiq were to be sold in whole or in part or acquire another company or its business in whole or in part, your personal data may be transferred to a potential seller or purchaser of such company or business. 

## How long do we store your personal data?

The same type of personal data may be processed for different purposes and based on different legal grounds, for example processing which is based on our obligations to fulfill a contract with you, based on our legitimate interest or based on your consent. This means that certain personal data may still be stored by us even if you withdraw your consent and the processing that your consent concern ceases. This also means that certain personal data may be eliminated from one system because it is no longer necessary for one particular purpose, but still be stored in another system based on your consent or for another purpose for which the personal data is still necessary. In some cases, the cookies we use may include personal data; however, they currently do not. 

Personal data consisting of information about products you have purchased and your license management account will be stored for twenty (20) years (i) after you have unregistered your account or (ii) after your latest activity connected to your account, for back-up purposes and in order support Zynaptiq with the possibility to provide the ability to re-download such products in the future. Other personal data connected to your Zynaptiq account will be processed until you unregister your account or ask us to delete certain data. If you have been inactive during the last three (3) years we will erase your account (save for the information about products you have purchased and your license management account. 

Personal data that we process in connection with your purchases of licenses and in order to administrate or to fulfill our obligations to you under a contract will be processed for as long as we have contractual obligations to you. If you have made a cancellation, claim or warranty request we will process your personal data for as long as the process regarding the cancellation, claim or warranty request is active. 

When we process personal data as a result of your communication with us, in for example support and customer service matters, the processing will continue until your support matter or customer service matter have been completed and will thereafter be stored for 24 months after your ticket is closed in order to fulfil our legitimate interest to develop our products and improve service. 

When we process personal data in order to analyze and develop our products and services the processing will continue for 24 months. 

When processing is made in order for us to comply with legal obligations, your personal data will be processed for as long as is set out in the relevant legal obligation. When processing is made in order to prevent and investigate abuse or violations of law the processing may be made up to 36 months. 

When personal data is processed based on your consent the processing will continue until you withdraw your consent, or otherwise indicate to us that you no longer wish to be subject to the processing. 

When we process your personal data based on our legitimate interest, you have the right to object to the processing at any time. 

Your personal data may be stored longer than the above, to the extent we are required to do so by law, regulation or decisions made by authorities. 

## What rights do you have relating to the processing of your personal data?

Below you will find a description of your rights regarding the processing of your personal data. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, you are welcome to contact us by using the contact details set out below. 

_Right to obtain access to information_

You have the right to obtain access to information about the personal data we process about you and you also have the right to request correction of your personal data. 

_Right to control of your personal data_

You have the right to object, at any time, to processing of your personal data which is based on our legitimate interest. Under certain circumstances, for example if you withdraw all or part of a given consent on the processing of personal data, object to our processing or if you think that the processing is not necessary for the stated purposes, you have the right to request erasure or restriction of your personal data. Under certain circumstances, you also have the right to receive the personal data concerning you that you have provided us with, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transfer such data to another data controller. 

_Right to withdraw your consent_

You have the right to withdraw a given consent at any given time. The withdrawal of consent may, however, have no effect on our processing of your personal data for the period prior to the withdrawal took place. You also have the right, at any time, to object to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing and profiling. 

_Right to submit complaints_

If you have any complaints regarding our processing of your personal data, you have the right to submit such complaint to the German Supervisory Authority or to another supervisory authority. 

All communication and measures taken by us in connection with you exercising your rights is provided free of charge. If you make an obviously unreasonable or unjustified request, we do, however, reserve the right to charge you with a reasonable fee for the costs that arise for us in order to provide you with the requested information or to take the steps necessary to fulfil your request or to decline such request. 

## Do you have any questions?

If you have any questions regarding the way Zynaptiq handles personal information, regarding the information in this Privacy Policy or if you have any requests regarding the processing of personal data, do not hesitate to get in touch with us through the [Contact Zynaptiq Support page](https://www.zynaptiq.com/support/support-form/) or send us an e-mail to support(at)zynaptiq.com. Our postal address is, Zynaptiq GmbH, Sandstr. 12, 30167 Hannover, Germany.
